<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
	<name>Hotkeys</name>
	<key>hotkeys</key>

	<!-- stable | unstable | beta | alpha -->
	<state>stable</state>

	<!-- 40x40px or bigger. Marketplace will resize it. -->
	<logo>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/JuanCarlosAcostaPeraba/glpi-hotkeys-plugin/main/assets/logo.png</logo>

	<description>
		<short>
			<en>Save tickets and ticket tasks using keyboard shortcuts.</en>
			<es_ES>Guarda tickets y tareas de tickets mediante atajos de teclado.</es_ES>
			<fr_FR>Enregistrez les tickets et les tâches de ticket à l'aide de raccourcis clavier.</fr_FR>
		</short>
		<long>
			<en><![CDATA[
**Hotkeys** is a productivity enhancement plugin for GLPI that lets technicians save ticket forms and ticket task forms using keyboard shortcuts.

It automatically adds:

- **Smart Save (`Ctrl + S` / `Cmd + S`)**: Intelligently saves the active form. If a ticket task form is active or open in a modal, it saves the task. Otherwise, it saves the ticket.
- **Force-Save Ticket (`Ctrl + Alt + S` / `Cmd + Alt + S`)**: Directly saves the main ticket form, ignoring any open task forms.
- **Toggleable Help Badge**: Close the floating badge to declutter the screen, and reopen it or toggle the shortcut helper anytime by pressing the `?` key (ignored when typing in text fields or TinyMCE editors).
- **Safe Submission Guard**: Prevents double submissions and holding keys, and respects HTML5 native browser validations.
- **Non-blocking Visual Feedback**: Displays a small toast notification on save operations.
- **Admin Configuration Screen**: Turn shortcuts on/off, capture key combinations with a live keyboard recorder, and toggle visual alerts.
 
**Features:**
- Platform-native modifier handling (`Cmd` on macOS and `Ctrl` elsewhere)
- Full timeline and AJAX support (remains functional after dynamic updates and dialog popups)
- Multi-language support (English, Spanish, French)
- Dark theme compatible
- Zero performance impact
 
Designed to improve visibility, speed up operations, and enhance ticket management efficiency for support teams.
 
Developed for real-world usage at the **Hospital Universitario de Canarias (HUC)**.
			]]></en>
 
			<es_ES><![CDATA[
**Hotkeys** es un plugin de productividad para GLPI que permite a los técnicos guardar formularios de tickets y tareas de tickets mediante atajos de teclado.
 
Añade automáticamente:
 
- **Guardado Inteligente (`Ctrl + S` / `Cmd + S`)**: Guarda de forma inteligente el formulario activo. Si el formulario de tarea está activo o abierto en un modal, guarda la tarea. De lo contrario, guarda el ticket.
- **Forzar Guardado de Ticket (`Ctrl + Alt + S` / `Cmd + Alt + S`)**: Guarda directamente el formulario del ticket, ignorando cualquier tarea abierta.
- **Botón de Ayuda Interactivo**: Oculta el botón flotante para despejar la pantalla y vuelve a abrirlo o muestra el panel de atajos en cualquier momento pulsando la tecla `?` (se ignora automáticamente al escribir en campos de texto o editores TinyMCE).
- **Protección de Envío Seguro**: Evita envíos duplicados o por repetición de teclas, y respeta las validaciones nativas de HTML5.
- **Comentarios Visuales**: Muestra una alerta toast flotante no bloqueante durante la operación de guardado.
- **Pantalla de Configuración**: Activa o desactiva atajos, captura combinaciones con un grabador de teclado en vivo y gestiona alertas.
 
**Características:**
- Manejo nativo de modificadores (`Cmd` en macOS y `Ctrl` en otros sistemas)
- Soporte dinámico para timeline y AJAX (funciona tras recargas dinámicas y popups)
- Soporte multiidioma (Inglés, Español, Francés)
- Compatible con tema oscuro
- Sin impacto en el rendimiento
 
Diseñado para mejorar la visibilidad, acelerar la atención técnica y mejorar la eficiencia en la gestión diaria de tickets.
 
Desarrollar para uso real en el **Hospital Universitario de Canarias (HUC)**.
			]]></es_ES>
 
			<fr_FR><![CDATA[
**Hotkeys** est un plugin de productivité pour GLPI qui permet aux techniciens d'enregistrer des formulaires de tickets et de tâches de tickets à l'aide de raccourcis clavier.
 
Il ajoute automatiquement :
 
- **Sauvegarde Intelligente (`Ctrl + S` / `Cmd + S`)** : Enregistre intelligemment le formulaire actif. Si une tâche est active ou ouverte dans un modal, elle enregistre la tâche. Sinon, elle enregistre le ticket.
- **Forcer la Sauvegarde du Ticket (`Ctrl + Alt + S` / `Cmd + Alt + S`)** : Enregistre directement le formulaire du ticket principal, en ignorant les formulaires de tâches ouverts.
- **Bouton d'Aide Interactif** : Masquez le bouton flottant pour libérer l'écran et réaffichez-le ou ouvrez le panneau des raccourcis à tout moment en appuyant sur la touche `?` (ignoré lors de la saisie dans des champs de texte ou TinyMCE).
- **Garde d'Envoi Sécurisé** : Évite les doubles envois accidentels et respecte les validations HTML5 natives du navigateur.
- **Notification Visuelle Non Bloquante** : Affiche un toast flottant lors des opérations d'enregistrement.
- **Écran de Configuration** : Activez/désactivez les raccourcis, enregistrez des combinaisons en direct et configurez les retours visuels.
 
**Fonctionnalités :**
- Gestion des modificateurs native (`Cmd` sur macOS et `Ctrl` ailleurs)
- Support complet de la timeline et d'AJAX (fonctionne après les rechargements dynamiques et les fenêtres modales)
- Support multilingue (Anglais, Espagnol, Français)
- Compatible avec le thème sombre
- Aucun impact sur les performances
 
Conçu pour améliorer la rapidité de traitement et optimiser l'efficacité de la gestion des tickets pour les équipes de support.
 
Développé pour une utilisation réelle à l'**Hospital Universitario de Canarias (HUC)**.
			]]></fr_FR>
		</long>
	</description>
 
	<homepage>https://github.com/JuanCarlosAcostaPeraba/glpi-hotkeys-plugin</homepage>
 
	<download>https://github.com/JuanCarlosAcostaPeraba/glpi-hotkeys-plugin/releases</download>
	<issues>https://github.com/JuanCarlosAcostaPeraba/glpi-hotkeys-plugin/issues</issues>
	<readme>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/JuanCarlosAcostaPeraba/glpi-hotkeys-plugin/main/README.md</readme>
 
	<authors>
		<author>Juan Carlos Acosta Perabá</author>
	</authors>
 
	<versions>
		<version>
			<num>1.1.0</num>
			<compatibility>~11.0.0</compatibility>
			<download_url>https://github.com/JuanCarlosAcostaPeraba/glpi-hotkeys-plugin/releases/download/v1.1.0/glpi-hotkeys-plugin-1.1.0.zip</download_url>
		</version>
		<version>
			<num>1.0.0</num>
			<compatibility>~11.0.0</compatibility>
			<download_url>https://github.com/JuanCarlosAcostaPeraba/glpi-hotkeys-plugin/releases/download/v1.0.0/hotkeys-1.0.0.zip</download_url>
		</version>
	</versions>

	<langs>
		<lang>en_GB</lang>
		<lang>es_ES</lang>
		<lang>fr_FR</lang>
	</langs>

	<license>GPL v3+</license>

	<tags>
		<en>
			<tag>hotkeys</tag>
			<tag>shortcuts</tag>
			<tag>ticket</tag>
			<tag>task</tag>
			<tag>save</tag>
			<tag>productivity</tag>
			<tag>ui-enhancement</tag>
			<tag>configuration</tag>
		</en>
		<es_ES>
			<tag>atajos</tag>
			<tag>teclado</tag>
			<tag>ticket</tag>
			<tag>tarea</tag>
			<tag>guardar</tag>
			<tag>configuracion</tag>
		</es_ES>
		<fr_FR>
			<tag>raccourcis</tag>
			<tag>clavier</tag>
			<tag>ticket</tag>
			<tag>tâche</tag>
			<tag>sauvegarder</tag>
			<tag>configuration</tag>
		</fr_FR>
	</tags>

	<screenshots>
		<screenshot>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/JuanCarlosAcostaPeraba/glpi-hotkeys-plugin/main/assets/screenshots/screenshot-config.png</screenshot>
		<screenshot>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/JuanCarlosAcostaPeraba/glpi-hotkeys-plugin/main/assets/screenshots/screenshot-save-toast.png</screenshot>
	</screenshots>

</root>
